Guide to the Abraham Aronow Photographs
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Scenes from the American West, 1982-2008; Series III; 1; (5 boxes)
  - Photographic Prints 11 x 14 Inches
    - California
      - San Francisco
        - Divine Shine and the Descent of Man. The Palace of the Legion of Honor, San Francisco, California, 2006 July 13 (Box 22, Folder 554)
        - Reaching Out, Emilio's Party, San Francisco, California, 1997 June 29 (Box 22, Folder 555)
      - San Gregorio
        - Old Cypress, Stage Road, San Gregorio, California, 2008 January 16 (Box 22, Folder 556)
      - Sawyer's Bar
        - Dogwood in Spring, near Sawyer's Bar, California, 2006 May 20 (Box 22, Folder 557)
      - Woodland Hills
        - Girls at the Mall, Woodland Hills, California, 1998 July 21 (Box 22, Folder 558)
      - Yosemite National Park
        - Branch Boulder, Tuolumne Meadows, Yosemite National Park, California, undated (Box 22, Folder 559)
        - Glacial Polish, Yosemite National Park, California, undated (Box 22, Folder 560)
      - Unidentified locations in California
        - Bucolic Scene, Route 101, Northern California, undated (Box 22, Folder 561)
        - Christmas Tree Farm, Northern California, undated (Box 22, Folder 562)
        - Radiator, Detail, Old Ford, Rural California, undated (Box 22, Folder 563)
        - Live Oak, Rural California, undated (Box 22, Folder 564)
    - Colorado
      - Interior Salvation, Store Window, Crested Butte, Colorado, undated (Box 23, Folder 565)
    - Nevada
      - Gerlach
        - Abandoned Building, Interior, near Gerlach, Nevada, 2002 June1 (Box 23, Folder 566)
        - Black Rock, White Cloud, The Playa, near Gerlach, Nevada, 2002 June 2 (Box 23, Folder 567)
        - Dashing Dragon, The Playa, near Gerlach, Nevada, 2002 June 2 (Box 23, Folder 568)
        - High Noon, The Playa, near Gerlach, Nevada, 2002 June 2 (Box 23, Folder 569)
        - The Playa, near Gerlach, Nevada, 2002 June 2 (Box 23, Folder 570-571)
        - Train, Stage Left, near Gerlach, Nevada, 2006 June 1 (Box 23, Folder 572)
      - Rhyolite
        - Crumbling Façade, Rhyolite, Nevada, undated (Box 23, Folder 573)
      - Virginia City
        - Church Detail, Virginia City, Nevada, undated (Box 23, Folder 574)
        - Old Fire Engine, Detail, Virginia City, Nevada, undated (Box 23, Folder 575)
    - New Mexico
      - Ranchos de Taos
        - San Francisco de Asis Mission Church, Ranchos de Taos, Taos, New Mexico, undated (Box 23, Folder 576)
      - Santa Fe
        - Doorway Detail, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 2003 February 25 (Box 23, Folder 577)
        - Entryway Detail, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 2003 February 25 (Box 23, Folder 578)
        - Mailbox Detail, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 2003 February 24 (Box 23, Folder 579)
        - Playground Detail, Night, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 2003 February 24 (Box 23, Folder 580)
        - Winter Schoolyard, Night, Santa Fe, New Mexico, undated (Box 23, Folder 581)
    - Oregon
      - Gown in Shop Window, Night, Portland, Oregon, 2003 April 9 (Box 23, Folder 582)
      - Said Reaching for Art, Night, Portland, Oregon, 2003 April 12 (Box 23, Folder 583)
      - Sprinkler Men, Portland, Oregon, 2003 April 9 (Box 23, Folder 584)
    - Texas
      - Antique Shop, Route 84, Western Texas, undated (Box 23, Folder 585)
      - Hot Weather Fur, Galveston, Texas, 2002 March 10 (Box 23, Folder 586)
- Portraits Acquired in 2012, 1983-1984; Series IV; 0.1; (1 box)
  - Shockley, William, 1983 August 17; 6 black and white contact sheets, 8 x 10 inches and smaller, with 36 studio portraits of Shockley (Box 24, Folder 587)
  - Stegner, Wallace, 1984 February 22; 1 black and white photographic print, 11 x 17 inches (Box 24, Folder 588)
- Portraits and Views Acquired in 2017, 1982-2017; Series V; 0.46 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Photographs that chiefly consists of portraits of individuals involved in the arts, letters, and sciences with images created between 1982 and 2012 and printed between 2002 and 2017. Many of the portrait subjects relate to the American West. A small group of views primarily document sites related to water use in the American West.
  Organized into three subseries: Portraits on Inkjet Prints, 8.5 x 11 inches; Portraits on Photographic Prints, 11 x 14 inches; and Views on Photographic Prints, 11 x 14 inches.
  - Portraits on Inkjet Prints, 8.5 x 11 inches
    Portraits on black and white inkjet prints. Biographical and image contextual notes adapted from information provided by Aronow upon acquisition.
    Arranged alphabetically by surname of the subject.
    - Adams, Ansel, 1902-1984, printed on 2016 February 24; portrait created on 1982 August 1 (Box 25, Folder 589)
      Biographical / Historical
      Adams was a photographer, author, musician, and environmentalist
      Adams at his home in Carmel Highlands, California, beside a ceramic sculpture by Juan Hamilton, 1945-, on a wooden turntable made by Abe Aronow and Alice Aronow on his piano
    - Adams, Ansel, 1902-1984, printed on 2016 February 24; portrait created on 1983 October 30 (Box 25, Folder 590)
      Adams at the home of John Sexton in Carmel, California
    - Adams, Virginia, 1904-2000, printed on 2016 February 20; portrait created on 1982 August 1 (Box 25, Folder 591)
      Adams, born Virginia Best, was the wife of Ansel Adams
      Adams at her home in Carmel Highlands, California
    - Ames, Bruce N., 1928-, printed on 2015 December 9; portrait created on 1983 July 13 (Box 25, Folder 592)
      Ames is a biochemist and professor at University of California, Berkeley
      Ames at his laboratory at the University of California, Berkeley, in Berkeley, California
    - Arrau, Claudio, 1903-1991, printed on 2016 February 21; portrait created on 1986 March 3 (Box 25, Folder 593)
      Arrau was a Chilean concert pianist
      Arrau at a hotel in San Francisco, California
    - Asawa, Ruth, 1926-2013, printed on 2016 February 19; portrait created on 1983 May 4 (Box 25, Folder 594)
      Asawa was an artist, sculptor, and close friend of Imogen Cunningham, 1883-1976
      Asawa at her home in San Francisco, California
    - Barnbaum, Bruce, 1943-, printed on 2016 February 18; portrait created on 1985 March 21 (Box 25, Folder 595)
      Barnbaum is a photographer
      Barnbaum at Carmel, California
    - Belli, Melvin, 1907-1996, printed on 2015 December 21; portraits created on 1984 July 15; 2 inkjet prints (Box 25, Folder 596)
      Belli was an attornery known as "King of Torts"
      Belli at his home in San Francisco, California
    - Berg, Paul, 1926-, printed on 2016 February 20; portrait created on 1983 July 25 (Box 25, Folder 597)
      Berg is biochemist and professor at Stanford University as well as the recipient of the Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 1980
      Berg at his office in Palo Alto, California
    - Bessie, Alvah Cecil, 1904-1985, printed on 2016 February 24; portrait created on 1983 May 16 (Box 25, Folder 598)
      Bessie was a novelist and screen writer
      Bessie his home in San Francisco, California
    - Bettelheim, Bruno, 1903-1990, printed on 2016 February 20; portrait created on 1983 August 14 (Box 25, Folder 599)
      Bettelheim was an Austrian-born psychologist, analyst, and author
      Bettelheim at University of California Extension in San Francisco, California
    - Bishop, G. Paul (George Paul), 1915-1998, printed on 2016 February 18; portrait created on 1984 March 29 (Box 25, Folder 600)
      Bishop was a photographer and teacher
      Bishop in his studio at his home in Berkeley, California
    - Bridges, Harry, 1901-1990, printed on 2015 September 30; portrait created on 1983 May 23 (Box 25, Folder 601)
      Bridges was an Australian-born labor leader
      Bridges at his home in San Francisco, California
    - Brower, David, 1912-2000, printed on 2016 February 20; portraits created on 1983 August 18; 2 inkjet prints (Box 25, Folder 602)
      Brower was an environmentalist
      Brower at his home in Berkeley, California
    - Casanave, Martha Pearson, 1945-, printed on 2016 February 18; portrait created on 1984 August 27 (Box 25, Folder 603)
      Casanave is a photographer
      Casanave at her home in Carmel, California
    - Criley, Richard Lawrence, 1911-2000, printed on 2016 January 21; portrait created on 1983 June 21 (Box 25, Folder 604)
      Criley was a left-wing political activist
      Criley at his home in Carmel Highlands, California
    - Dahl-Wolfe, Louise, 1895-1989, printed on 2016 March 10; portrait created on 1986 June 13 (Box 25, Folder 605)
      Dahl-Wolfe was a fashion photography pioneer
      Dahl-Wolfe at her home in New Jersey
    - Dolby, Ray Milton, 1933-2013, printed on 2016 February 19; portrait created on 1983 July 8 (Box 25, Folder 606)
      Dolby was an audio engineer
      Dolby at his home in San Francisco, California
    - Dutton, Allen A., 1922-, printed on 2016 February 22; portrait created on 1986 March 17 (Box 25, Folder 607)
      Dutton is a photographer and artist
      Dutton at his home in Prescott, Arizona
    - Everson, William, 1912-1994, printed on 2016 February 23; portraits created on 1985 January 26; 2 inkjet prints (Box 25, Folder 608)
      Everson, also known as Brother Antoninus, was poet and literary critic
      Everson at his home, "Kingfisher Flat", near Santa Cruz, California
    - Friedman, Milton, 1912-2006, printed on 2016 February 24; portrait created on 1983 November 3 (Box 25, Folder 609)
      Friedman was an economist and recipient of the Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 1976
      Friedman at his home in San Francisco, California
    - Fulton, Jack, 1939-, printed on 2016 February 18; portrait created on 1985 April 4 (Box 25, Folder 610)
      Fulton is a photographer and educator
      Fulton in his office at the San Francisco Art Institute in San Francisco, California
    - Garnett, William A., 1916-2006, printed on 2016 February 21; portrait created on 1984 October 12 (Box 25, Folder 611)
      Garnett was an aerial photographer
      Garnett at the Sonoma County Airport in Sonoma, California
    - Gutmann, John, 1905-1998, printed on 2016 February 17; portrait created on 1985 July 29 (Box 25, Folder 612)
      Gutmann was a photographer and painter
      Gutmann at his home in San Francisco, California
    - Hamaguchi, Yōzō, 1909-2000, printed on 2016 February 21; portrait created on 1984 April 4 (Box 25, Folder 613)
      Hamaguchi was a mezzotint artist
      Hamaguchi at Vorpal Gallery in San Francisco, California
    - Hattersley, Ralph, 1938-2000, printed on 2016 March 10; portrait created on 1986 June 3 (Box 25, Folder 614)
      Hattersley was a photographer, teacher and author
      Hattersley at his home in Austin, Texas
    - Hayakawa, S. I. (Samuel Ichiyé), 1906-1992, printed on 2016 February 20; portrait created on 1983 October 5 (Box 25, Folder 615)
      Hayakowa was an academic and politician
      Hayakowa at his home in Greenbrae, California
    - Hooper, Jack, 1928-2014, printed on 2015 December 18; portrait created on 1984 April 8 (Box 25, Folder 616)
      Hooper was an artist
      Hooper at Vorpal Gallery in San Francisco, California
    - Huntington, Witherill, 1949-, printed on 2016 February 22; portrait created on 1985 January 14 (Box 25, Folder 617)
      Huntington is a photographer
      Huntington at his home in Carmel, California
    - Jacobi, Lotte, 1896-1990, printed on 2016 February 24; portrait created on 1984 June 28 (Box 25, Folder 618)
      Jacobi was a photographer
      Jacobi at her home in Deering, New Hampshire
    - Leibovitz, Annie, 1949-, printed on 2016 February 23; portrait created on 1985 July 25 (Box 25, Folder 619)
      Leibovitz is a photographer
      Leibovitz at Carmel Valley, California
    - Lipset, Hal, 1919-1997, printed on 2016 January 21; portrait created on 1983 April 8 (Box 25, Folder 620)
      Lipset was a private investigator
      Lipset at his office in San Francisco, California
    - Maloof, Sam, 1916-2009, printed on 2016 February 20; portrait created on 1983 December 11 (Box 25, Folder 621)
      Maloof was a furniture designer and woodworker
      Maloof at Berkeley, California
    - Mark, Mary Ellen, 1940-2015, printed on 2016 February 24; portrait created on 1984 June 28 (Box 25, Folder 622)
      Mark was a photojournalist and documentary photographer
      Mark at her home in New York City
    - McPhee, Laura, 1958-, printed on 2017 January 2; portrait created on 2002 April 24 (Box 25, Folder 623)
      McPhee is a photographer
      McPhee at her home in Brookline, Massachusetts
    - Minsky, Marvin, 1927-2016, printed on 2016 February 19; portrait created on 1983 August 31 (Box 25, Folder 624)
      Minsky was a mathematician and artificial intelligence pioneer
      Minsky at his office at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in Cambridge, Massachusetts
    - Mitford, Jessica, 1917-1996, printed on 2016 February 20; portrait created on 1983 September 18 (Box 25, Folder 625)
      Mitford was an author and journalist
      Mitford at her home in Berkeley, California
    - Nakashima, George, 1905-1990, printed on 2016 February 19; portrait created on 1983 August 27 (Box 25, Folder 626)
      Nakashima was an architect, artist and woodworker
      Nakashima at his studio in New Hope, Pennsylvania
    - Oppenheimer, Frank, 1912-1985, printed on 2015 December 7; portrait created on 1983 December 13 (Box 25, Folder 627)
      Oppenheimer was a particle physicist, rancher, and teacher
      Oppenheimer at San Francisco, California
    - Rainier, Chris, 1958-, printed on 2016 February 21; portrait created on 1984 May 24 (Box 25, Folder 628)
      Rainier is a documentary photographer
      Rainier at Carmel, California
    - Rowland, Adele, 1916-2015, printed on 2016 February 18; portrait created on 1985 September 19 (Box 25, Folder 629)
      Rowland, born Eugenia H. Rowland, was a photographer and Dominican sister
      Rowland at her home at Dominican University of California in San Rafael, California
    - Saunders, J. B. deC. M. (John Bertrand deCusance Morant), 1903-1991, printed on 2015 December 18; portraits created on 1984 March 30; 2 inkjet prints (Box 25, Folder 630)
      Saunders was an anatomist, historian of medicine and Chancellor of University of California, San Francisco
      Saunders at his home in San Francisco, California
    - Stoumen, Louis Clyde, 1917-1991, printed on 2016 February 21; portrait created on 1986 February 28 (Box 25, Folder 631)
      Stoumen was a photographer, film director and producer
      Stoumen at Vision Gallery in San Francisco, California
    - Teller, Edward, 1908-2003, printed on 2016 February 19; portrait created on 1983 July 25 (Box 25, Folder 632)
      Teller was a theoretical physicist
      Teller at his office in Palo Alto, California
    - Tucker, Toba Pato, 1935-, printed on 2016 January 21; portraits created on 1983 August 28 (Box 25, Folder 633)
      Tucker is a photographer
      Tucker at her home in New York City
    - Verdon, René, 1924-2011, printed on 2015 December 6; portrait created on 1984 March 1 (Box 25, Folder 634)
      Verdon was a chef and restauranteur
      Verdon at Le Trianon Restaurant in San Francisco, California
    - Vestal, David, 1924-2013, printed on 2016 March 9; portrait created on 1986 June 7 (Box 25, Folder 635)
      Vestal was a photographer, author, teacher,and critic
      Vestal at his home in Bethlehem, Connecticut
    - Weber, Albert C., 1930-2016, printed on 2015 March 14; portrait created on 1985 January 14 (Box 25, Folder 636)
      Weber was a photographer and teacher
      Weber at his home in Carmel Highlands, California; print by Mark Citret, 1949-
    - Wolcott, Marion Post, 1910-1990, printed on 2016 February 18; portrait created on 1985 March 25 (Box 25, Folder 637)
      Post Wolcott was a photographer
      Post Wolcott at her home in Santa Barbara
  - Portraits on Photographic Prints, 11 x 14 inches
    Portraits on selenium toned black and white silver gelatin prints, except for a color print of Jane Goodall. Biographical and image contextual notes adapted from information provided by Aronow upon acquisition.
    Arranged alphabetically by surname of the subject followed by a portrait of an unidentified man.
    - Aronow, Abraham, 1940-, printed 2012 March 1; portrait created 2011 October 28 (Box 26, Folder 638)
      Self-portrait at the Center for Creative Photography at the University of Arizona in Tucson, Arizona
    - Banducci, Enrico, 1922-2007, printed 2014 November 9; portrait created 1983 June 28 (Box 26, Folder 639)
      Banducci was an impresario and nightclub owner
      Banducci, Enrico at his nightclub, "the hungry i," in North Beach, San Francisco, California
    - Bernhard, Ruth, 1906-2006, printed on 2013 May 16; portrait created 1985 September 28 (Box 26, Folder 640)
      Bernhard was a photographer
      Bernhard at her home in San Francisco, California
    - Bristol, Horace, 1908-1997, printed on 2012 December 12; portrait created 1993 October 9 (Box 26, Folder 641)
      Bristol was a American documentary photographer
      Bristol at his home in Ojai, California
    - Bunnell, Peter C., 1937-, printed on 2012 May 3; portrait created 1994 June 15 (Box 26, Folder 642)
      Bunnell is an author and historian of photography
      Bunnell at his home in Princeton, New Jersey
    - Calvin, Melvin, 1911-1997, printed on 2015 March 15; portrait created 1983 June 6 (Box 26, Folder 643)
      Calvin was a biochemist and and recipient of the Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 1961
      Calvin in his office at the University of California, Berkeley, in Berkeley, California
    - Carpenter, Arthur Espenet, 1920-2006, printed on 2009 May 2; portrait created 1983 January 19 (Box 26, Folder 644)
      Carpenter was a woodworker and furniture designer
      Carpenter at his home in Bolinas, California
    - Coke, Van Deren, 1921-2004, printed on 2011 August 13; portrait created 1984 March 6 (Box 26, Folder 645)
      Coke was a photographer and museum professional
      Coke at the San Francisco Museum of Modern Art in San Francisco, California
    - Commager, Henry Steele, 1902-1998, printed on 2014 October 9; portrait created 1984 July 1 (Box 26, Folder 646)
      Commager was a historian and author
      Commager at his home in Amherst, Massachusetts
    - Djerassi, Carl, 1923-2015, printed on 2010 April 21; portrait created 2010 March 15 (Box 26, Folder 647)
      Djerassi was a chemist, novelist, and playwright
      Djerassi at his home in San Francisco, California
    - Doolittle, James Harold, 1896-1993, printed on 2014 July 5; portrait created 1985 July 25 (Box 26, Folder 648)
      Doolittle was an aviation pioneer and recipient of the Medal of Honor
      Doolittle at his home in Carmel, California
    - Erikson, Erik H. (Erik Homburger), 1902-1994, printed on 2014 September 13; portrait created 1985 December 18 (Box 26, Folder 649)
      Erikson was a pschologist, sociologist and author
      Erikson at his home in Marin County, California
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1919-, printed circa 1992; portrait created 1992 April 18; 2 photographic prints (Box 26, Folder 650)
      Ferlinghetti was a poet, painter, publisher and activist
      Ferlinghetti at his studio in San Francisco, California
    - Goodall, Jane, 1934-, printed circa 2013; portrait created 1984 April 15 (Box 26, Folder 651)
      Goodall is a primatologist and author
      Goodall at San Francisco, California
    - Hahn, Betty, 1940-, printed on 2013 April 10; portrait created 2002 February 27 (Box 26, Folder 652)
      Hahn is a photographer
      Hahn at her home in Albuquerque, New Mexico
    - Harbutt, Charles, 1935-2015, printed on 2013 March 26; portrait created 2004 September 24 (Box 26, Folder 653)
      Harbutt was a photographer and teacher
      Harbutt at his home in New York City
    - Heick, William, 1916-2012, printed on 2014 November 8; portrait created 2002 September 18 (Box 26, Folder 654)
      Heick was a photographer
      Heick at his home in Marin County, California
    - Hido, Todd, 1968-, printed on 2013 March 29; portrait created 2002 February 7 (Box 26, Folder 655)
      Hido is a photographer
      Hido at his home in San Francisco, California
    - Jachna, Joseph D., 1935-2016, printed on 2013 January 16; portrait created 2007 November 29 (Box 26, Folder 656)
      Jachna was a photographer and teacher
      Jachna at the Columbia College of Art in Chicago, Illinois
    - James, Daniel, 1911-1988, printed on 2014 November 8; portrait created 1983 June 22 (Box 26, Folder 657)
      James was an author and motion picture director also known by his pseudonyms Daniel Hyatt and Danny Santiago
      James at his home in Carmel Highlands, California
    - Josephson, Kenneth, 1932-, printed on 2013 January 14; portrait created 2007 November 30 (Box 26, Folder 658)
      Josephson is a photographer and teacher
      Josephson at the Columbia College of Art in Chicago, Illinois
    - Kasten, Barbara, 1936-, printed on 2013 January 8; portrait created 2007 December 8 (Box 26, Folder 659)
      Kasten is a photographer
      Kasten at the Columbia College of Art, Chicago
    - Kornberg, Arthur, 1918-2007, printed on 2014 November 19; portrait created 1983 June 3 (Box 26, Folder 660)
      Kornberg was a biochemist and and recipient of the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine in 1959
      Kornberg in his office at Stanford University in Palo Alto, California
    - Lehrer, Tom, 1928-, printed on 2012 May 22; portrait created 1983 June 9 (Box 26, Folder 661)
      Lehrer is a musician, singer-songwriter, satirist, and mathematician
      Lehrer at Santa Cruz, California
    - Lyons, Nathan, 1930-2016, printed on 2013 January 16; portrait created 1983 June 9 (Box 26, Folder 662)
      Lyons was a photographer, curator, and educator
      Lyons at New York City
    - Morell, Abelardo, 1948-, printed on 2012 March 30; portrait created 2002 April 23 (Box 26, Folder 663)
      Morell is a photographer
      Morell at his home in Boston, Massachusetts
    - Muniz, Vik, 1961-, printed on 2012 May 24; portrait created 2002 June 16 (Box 26, Folder 664)
      Muniz is a photographer
      Muniz at his home in Brooklyn, New York City
    - Newhall, Beaumont, 1908-1993, printed on 2013 January 26; portraits created 1983 June 21; 2 photographic prints (Box 26, Folder 665)
      Newhall was a photographer, historian, and curator
      Newhall at the home of Ansel Adams in Carmel Highlands, California
    - Nixon, Nicholas, 1947-, printed on 2012 April 4; portrait created 2002 April 23 (Box 26, Folder 666)
      Nixon is photographer
      Nixon at his home in Boston, Massachusetts
    - Noggle, Anne, 1922-2005, printed on 2013 April 16; portraits created 2012 February 27; 2 photographic prints (Box 26, Folder 667)
      Noggle was a photographer and aviator
      Noggle at her home in Albuquerque, New Mexico
    - Partridge, Rondal, 1917-2015, printed on 2012 November 7; portrait created 1985 February 12 (Box 26, Folder 668)
      Partridge was a photographer, as well as a son of Roi Partridge, 1888-1984, and Imogen Cunningham, 1883-1976, and an assistant to both Dorothea Lange, 1895-1965, and Ansel Adams
      Partridge at his home in Oakland, California
    - Plachy, Sylvia, 1943-, printed on 2013 March 14; portrait created 1994 November 9 (Box 26, Folder 669)
      Plachy is a photographer
      Plachy at her home in New York City
    - Quick, Herb, 1925-2006, printed on 2013 March 11; portrait created 2003 June 30 (Box 26, Folder 670)
      Quick was a photographer and teacher
      Quick at his home in Riverside, California
    - Rapoport, Sonya, 1923-2015, printed on 2012 October 31; portrait created 2012 July 6 (Box 26, Folder 671)
      Rapoport was an artist